DAVID CORNISH

FULL STACK SOFTWARE **DEVELOPER**

CONTACT



615.939.1934



dcornish84@gmail.com



in linkedin.com/in/david-L-cornish



github.com/dcornish84

ABOUT ME

The path to software development has been long and winding, but a few things have crystalized along the way.. I need an outlet for my creativity, I love new technology, and I thrive in a team based environment. I'm an avid Liverpool supporter, cat dad, coffee nerd, and outdoor enthusiast.

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

AUDIO TECHNOLOGY SAE INSTITUTE NASHVILLE

BACHELOR OF ARTS. PSYCHOLOGY UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE

EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

6 MONTH FULL STACK BOOTCAMP | AUG 2019 - FEB 2020

- Front End Capstone. Built a browser based application utilizing React, Reactstrap, Javascript, HTML, and CSS called RecordCollector. Called an external API to return album information that is saved to a catalogue or wishlist with full CRUD functionality.
- Celebrity Tribute. Worked with a team to create a tribute website for Amy Winehouse using just HTML and CSS.
- Welcome to Nashville. Worked with a team to create a tourism application for a client interested in the sports scene in Nashville. Utilized the Ticketmaster API to create an itinerary relevant to the client's interests. Built with Javascript, HTML, and CSS.
- Nutshell. Worked with a team to create an application for a goth sweet 16 party. The application displays user specific news, task list, event list, chat, and friends list. Each module utilized CRUD functionality. Built with Javascript, HTML, and CSS.
- Nutshell React. Worked with a team to create an application to manage the social lives of vampires. The application displays user specific news, task list, event list, chat, and friends list. Each module utilized CRUD functionality. Built with HTML, CSS, React.js, and Reactstrap.

F&B MANAGER

OMNI HOTELS AND RESORTS | JUL 2016 - JUL 2019

- Endeavored to uncover employee strengths and put them in positions to succeed
- Provided expedient service in a high volume, fast paced environment
- Projected sales and ordered products and supplies within budget

QUALITY MANAGEMENT SPECIALIST

CUMBERLAND HEIGHTS | JUN 2015 - JUL 2016

- Completed data analysis to compile monthly breakdowns of Patient Satisfaction Surveys, Incident Reports, Metrics, and Chart Audits
- Maintained and updated Policies and Procedures for the entire company

CLINICAL ASSOCIATE

CUMBERLAND HEIGHTS | JAN 2014 - JUN 2015

- Conducted 16 educational and experiential therapy groups a month
- State certified Ropes Course Instructor, utilizing certification in several experiential groups
- Utilized de-escalation techniques to ensure the well being of patients and staff

AUDIO ENGINEER

16TH EDGE STUDIOS | MAY 2011 - MAR 2014

• Utilized ProTools to record, edit, and mix tracks. Booked clients, maintained gear.